<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on arvdl notes</title>
    <link>https://arvdl.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on arvdl notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 08:34:39 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arvdl.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Gnome40 Manjaro Blank After Upgrade</title>
      <link>https://arvdl.github.io/posts/gnome40-manjaro-blank/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 08:34:39 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arvdl.github.io/posts/gnome40-manjaro-blank/</guid>
      <description>Intro  On the last update, Manjaro got so much packages updated, including the Gnome 40, Pacman 6.0, KDE 5.22.
I&amp;rsquo;m using gnome with nvidia driver, so when the update hit me, i got an error. When I login to Gnome, there just blank window without anything. But the strange thing is my Night Ligt is activated, so I though there is no problem about the kernel driver nvidia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Setup Zsh Tmux and Alacritty</title>
      <link>https://arvdl.github.io/posts/zsh-tmux-alacrity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 10:14:19 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arvdl.github.io/posts/zsh-tmux-alacrity/</guid>
      <description>So lets just get started for setting up zsh, tmux, and Alacritty.
   Alacritty Installation  Alacritty is fast and awesome terminal emulator with multi-platform support. My best choice an alternative for urxvt and terminator. I still considering for setting up st.
For archlinux user, install alacritty via pacman.
1  sudo pacman -S alacritty   Setup the alacritty configuration directory.
1  mkdir -p ~/.config/alacritty/; cd ~/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup Nvidia as Default Graphic Instead of Intel on Manjaro Gnome</title>
      <link>https://arvdl.github.io/posts/nvidia-instead-intel-manjaro-gnome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 13:53:55 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arvdl.github.io/posts/nvidia-instead-intel-manjaro-gnome/</guid>
      <description>Intro  So i got laptop with dual vga card Nvidia and Intel, the I install Manjaro with Gnome desktop on top of it.
Now, how I can set up Nvidia as default graphic driver instead of Intel on my manjaro system.
   Install nvidia graphic driver on manjaro  To install nvidia graphic driver on manjaro, run the following command.
1  sudo mhwd -a pci nonfree 0300   Now reboot the system and check again the installed nvidia driver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MAC Address Spoofing on Linux</title>
      <link>https://arvdl.github.io/posts/mac-address-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 11:26:54 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arvdl.github.io/posts/mac-address-linux/</guid>
      <description>Intro  MAC address (Media Access Control) is an identifier for our network devices that we use. It&amp;rsquo;s unique identifier, every network devices has different identities.
Mostly, MAC address are available at IEEE 802 networking technology such as Ethernet, Wi-Fi, and Bluetooth. And every devies that we uses such as Laptop, Computer, or even Smartphone has MAC address on top of it.
For this guide, i will show you how to automatically change MAC address of your Linux system using systemd-networkd service and using the NetworkManager application.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
